hello everybody um just a quick little
let you know about it we've gone ahead
I've gone ahead and broken out a new
phase of or stage whatever you want to
call it of the skill stack beginner
boost which I was playing around with
before but has kind of materialized at
this
point um so here it is if you look at
the
overview um you scroll
down so we have added the start which is
more about getting a job and what is the
strategy of getting a job and finding
out what you have to learn and
everything very very important stuff
please don't skip that and then we broke
out the basic stuff and that is what I'm
going to show you here in just a second
um so it's you know what are basic
computer skills what does it even mean
um the reason that we need to break out
a a stage here for this and the reason
that I haven't done it in the past is
because because this material is largely
assumed that you already know it and I
do want to tell a story about this so I
was teaching private school uh coding
Camp an after school coding Camp about
45 people at a private school and none
of them could install software on their
computers they all had different
computers someone was Windows someone
was Mac and then some of them had admin
access so they could do the installation
some couldn't some had to ask their mom
and dad to do it for them it was a mess
and I realized that most adults have
already covered this base
uh it is interesting to note that when I
actually did help out at the community
college for a while when I was you know
mentoring there that so many of the
people that were coming to the labs in
the commity co had never even used a
computer like it's I I know that that
seems interesting to say um but there is
still a huge digital divide in America
and there are people there are still
people in America who do not have a
computer and they they do not know how
to operate them they they it's it's less
and less a thing but it is still a thing
so so breaking out these skills and
knowing how to use a computer and how
the internet works how to install a
browser how to install software safely
um how to deal with viruses how to not
get owned um at a basic level as a just
a general computer user these are all
really essential skills and you may be
one of the lucky ones who was raised by
you know a family that gave you free
reign on the family PC and let you
install and they reimaged every once in
a while uh which we'll do a video about
that what is the best strategy for
helping somebody learn these skills at a
young age and how do you give them the
motivation and the sort of Reign that
they need um to be able to mess around
and explore safely on the computer um
but so when I talk about basic computer
skills this is what we're really talking
about and I'm just going to summarize it
really quickly we're talking about
learning how to type I'm talking about
you know purchasing a computer knowing
what computer to get whether to get a
Mac or a Linux machine whe I'm sorry a
Mac or you know a Linux machine or but
in this case mostly a Mac or Windows
machine why you might want one or the
other you know that sort of question if
you're just getting into Tech you may
not even know the right answer there so
and then stuff like how do you install
software on Windows how do you install
software on a Mac safely um what are the
different methods of that how do you use
the internet what is the internet is the
web the internet I mean these these are
questions that people literally don't
know the answers to so I know a lot of
you watching this video are like why is
he even doing this video but it's super
important that you have this handle
understanding your developer editor
options um I do think under knowing how
to edit files on your computer whether
it's simpl Tex notepad uh or vs code
which I think everybody should know how
to install um that becomes an issue
right because you got to be able to edit
files without knowing anything else any
of the fancy terminal stuff that we're
going to learn later um create a you
know proton mail accounts Gmail where do
you go for email why do you go there for
email um how does we already talked
about how the internet works how does
mail work how does it get shipped around
how do web pages actually work um and
that kind of thing how do I take notes
reliably and safely that that can be
backed up how do I back up my computer
how do I develop search Centric Habits
Like alt tab you know how do you know
how to do alt tab have you ever seen it
before you know how many people don't
how do I how about the spotlight bar
knowing how to use the spotlight bar to
save your time these are all skills that
involve basic computer usage which are
not taught anywhere they they may be
taught in some school systems and some
Community College but they're generally
not taught um leverage AI assistant
that's a new thing uh being able to ask
chat GPT online or or on the computer to
help you out these are these are things
that we you know more and more are being
assumed as basic computer skills so that
that change that has been broken out um
I'm not going to be able to cover all
this material anymore because we've
already moved past it we're going to try
to stay on the schedule which has us
doing websites creating basic websit
stuff for another week or two so we're
going to be doing all of that stuff but
but please be sure to check back if you
want to see the videos that are being
made there where are those videos made
um the videos are made during morning
morning boost time when I feel like it
uh that's when we're going to be making
them but other than that we're going to
be trying to catch up as many videos as
we can during the beginner boost radio
time on Saturdays and we're going to
continue to dedicate that 4our block
making these kind of videos so that is
that will hopefully catch you up uh with
where we are and um I will link this
video from the the opening page of the
beginner Booth so people can know why
it's changed perhaps um and that's all